JAHID KHAN

IT Engineer

<u>Application Developer</u>

developer.jahidkhan@gmail.com

+91-9111182311

(

Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India 452001

(in)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jahidkhan/

https://www.coderartstudio.com/

Summary _____

I am a tech enthusiast specialising in Flutter, React.js, and SpringBoot for web and mobile app development. My priority is to creating customized applications with micro services to deliver high-quality services and outcomes for my company.

Skills _____

Frameworks

- FLUTTER SDK ANDRIOD/KOTLIN NEXT.JS REACT.JS
- SPRINGBOOT/J2EE

<u>Familiarity Programming Languages</u>

• DART • C/C++ • JAVA • NODE.JS • PYTHON/GO LANG

Databases/Cloud Services/CMS/Other Technologies

- FIREBASE MONGODB BASIC SQL/POSTGRESQL STRIPE
- RENDER VARCEL VERSION CONTROL/GIT UI/UX DESIGN
- BLOC/GET PATTERN MVC/MVVM API

Experience _____

Tekzee Technologies pvt. ltd. | Indore Sr. Application Developer 11/2022 - present

- As a Application developer at Tekzee Technologies, I am
 working in remarkable range of projects, such as "OnDoor
 Concept" which is a high range of userbase (<u>link</u>). This app
 completely made on Native Android and java.
- "MyProfit Applications" (User, employee, and vendor) created on flutter framework for android and IOs user(link). Collaborating with team members and integrating various APIs, including third-party payment APIs, has significantly enhanced my development abilities Additionally, I comprehend that designing an appropriate folder structure is critical for optimising application performance and ensuring ease of maintenance.
- Develop an "e-commerce web application" using react.js, HTML, CSS,TAILWINDS, BOOTSTRAP and Thyme Leaf for the front-end.
- Java J2EE, Spring Boot, JDBC and SQL, hibernate will be used for the back-end

Wipro | Mumbai

Java Developer Intern(offered as Project Engineer) 02/2022 - 04/2023

ITNOBEL | Jaipur FLUTTER APPLICATION DEVELOPER

04/2021 - 12/2022

Nipsol, WFH, Gwalior SUPPORT MANAGER

06/2020 - 02/2021

- Experience includes developing and implementing client solutions using Flutter Framework, creating software applications in a test-driven development environment, designing and developing mobile apps, and writing backend code in node.js with mongodb database.
- In ItNobel I was work on multiple Android Application such as "EMS portal", "ACL Explosive APP" for factory barcode serialisation and generation of QR Code Bulk model as well as I was created there official web site of itnoble in flutter.
- Introduced incentives and team-building initiatives to enhance team spirit, monitored employee-customer interactions to assess service quality, and collaborated with other teams to resolve customer issues.
- Provided technical support to customers, troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
- Monitored customer service performance metrics and identified areas for improvement.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING _____

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya | Bhopal | Madhya Pradesh

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

08/2018 - 07/2022

- Bachelor of Technology Recipient
- Completed Overall GPA: 8.45

Madhya Pradesh Board of Secondary Education | Gohad | Madhya Pradesh

XII - Mathematics 04/2017 - 06/2018 • Percentage: 72.0 %

FREELANCING/PROJECTS _____

- <u>Team Connect App</u>: it is an Android app for employee management, featuring a unique attendance system, leave management, task assignment, progress tracking, and secure communication channels. The app simplifies employee management, allowing managers to easily keep track of their team's schedule and leave requests, while also providing an easy-to-use interface for employees to request time off and communicate with their team.
- <u>Cracker.At</u>: Introducing Cacker.At, a new app designed to help young engineers to choose a right career path. Its offer many tools such as pre- application company research, aptitude tests, access to campus, exam papers and personalized resume-building advice. The app aims to empower users with knowledge and resources to make informed decisions about their future career. <u>DOWNLOAD HERE</u>
- <u>Book-worm</u>: Bookworm is an app designed for book lovers to easily find secondhand books near them and connect with others in their community. With a user-friendly interface, users can chat with sellers and buyers, earn coins by selling their Certificate own books, and purchase new ones without breaking the bank. Bookworm is the perfect tool for discovering new books and connecting with other book enthusiasts in the area. <u>DOWNLOAD HERE</u>
- <u>Iskcondamodardesh.com</u>: Web Application for Dubai client. One of my outside India client that was a great experience for me to work on new requirement which help me to enhance my skill. This web app basically working in Dubai region. App create for the Hindu ritual of worship. Help to Schedule aarti, register user, connect users ,some videos and more.

Research Publication

HomDoc- A Diabetes Prediction Application

Certificate | App Download

A machine learning project has been developed to detect diabetes in individuals using Python, Flutter, Smoting, XGBoosting, and random Forest Classification. By analyzing a dataset of medical records, the application identifies patterns indicative of diabetes and provides users with an accurate diagnosis through a user-friendly interface. The use of Flutter allows for easy porting to multiple mobile platforms, while the use of Smoting, XGBoosting, and Random Forest Classification enhances the application's accuracy. This project has the potential to positively impact healthcare.

Published on International Journal of Research Publication and Reviews: 06 Jun 2022

| Certificates Achievements | |
|----------------------------------|--|
| | |

Java Full Stack Developer: Conduira (Gemini Solutions)

14 Jul 2022 - 27 Oct 2022

Java Core, Spring Boot, JSP/Servlet/Hibernate, React.js.

Web GIS Technology Certification: Indian Institute of Remote Sensing

21 Jun 2022 - 02 Jul 2022

Image Statistics | Basics of Remote Sensing | Geographical | Information System

CCNAv7: Introduction to Networks: NIIT Foundation By CISCO

Issued on: 10 Dec 2021

Configure switches | IPv4/IPv6 addressing schemes | data link | layer protocols and more

• CyberOps Associate: CISCO

Issued on: 8 Oct 2021

virtual machines | Use network monitoring tools to identify attacks against network protocols and services. cryptography on network security | Apply incident response models to manage network security incidents.

• Web Development : Internship(Sahu Technologies)

HTML | CSS | JAVASCRIPT | JQUERY

| ı | ^ | n | ~ | u | ^ | ~ | ^ | _ |
|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|
| ᆫ | а | н | ч | u | а | ч | C | > |

- Hindi Native
- English Professional